Matheus Elis da Silva

Bachelor's degree in Physics with an emphasis on Computational Physics from Universidade Federal Fluminense. Software Engineer with experience in software development, creation and maintenance of ETL processes, data process automation, cloud software architecture and microservices.

Academic Education

2015-2021

Bachelor, Physics with emphasis on Computational Physics; Universidade Federal Fluminense

Scholarship Monitor at the Sensebiliza Project (2017-2021)

Monograph entitled: Study of the Dynamics of Leprosy in the North of Brazil Via Agent-Based Modeling

Professional Experience

Software Developer FullStack: 2RP Net - Oct 2022 - Current

- Development and maintenance of Backend applications using Python and Golang languages.
- Creating and maintaining ETL pipelines for the data integration industry.
- Maintenance and management of SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL and OracleDB) and NoSQL (MongoDB, Google Datastore and Redis) databases.
- Creation of Microservices in Cloud environments (Google Cloud Run, Google Cloud Function and Google Kubernetes Engine).
- Application monitoring using Grafana, Google Cloud Logging and Google Cloud Monitoring.

Software Developer Back-End: ZAX - Mar 2022 - Sept 2022

- Development and maintenance of Back-End applications using Python and NodeJS languages.
- · Development of the company's internal ERP.
- CI/CD automation using GitHub Actions and Serverless Framework.
- · Use of Cloud tools such as AWS Lambda, AWS ECS, AWS Cloud Watch and AWS SQS.
- Maintenance and management of SQL databases (PostgreSQL and MySQL).

Software Developer Back-End: TrackCash - June 2021 - Apr 2022

- Development and maintenance of data automation applications using Python.
- Development and maintenance of applications to monitor automation routines.
- Development of internal CLI applications to manage ETL routines.

Technical Abilities

Programming Languages

- Python
- JavaScript

- TypeScript
- Golang
- HTML
- CSS
- Lua
- PHP

Frameworks and tools

- FastAPI
- Flask
- Django
- Spark
- Express
- React
- Bootstrap
- Laravel
- Gin
- Docker
- Docker Compose
- Kubernets
- Terraform

Soft Skill

- Languages:
 - Portuguese (Native),
 - English (Intermediary),
 - Spanish (Basic).
- Agile Methodologies:
 - Scrum,
 - Kanban.

matheus.elis.silva@gmail.com • +55 (12) 99669 4139 • 27 anos https://www.linkedin.com/in/matheuselisdasilva https://github.com/MatheusElis Barueri - São Paulo, Brasil